Inventory of the Benjamin Michael Levaco papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Benjamin Michael Levaco papers
1892-1998
93097
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes (0.8 linear feet)
Autobiographical writings, letters, certificates, bulletins, and photographs, relating to the Russian Jewish community in China from 1915 to 1950.
Levaco, Benjamin Michael, 1911-1998.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1993.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Russian businessman in China.
Scope and Content of Collection
Autobiographical writings, letters, certificates, bulletins, and photographs, relating to the Russian Jewish community in China from 1915 to 1950.
Jews--China.; Russians--China.
- Family file, 1892-1998 (Box 1)
  - School certificates, 1892, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Identification documents, undated (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Levaco family correspondence, 1950 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Mikhail Levaco poetry, 1949 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Moshev Levaco file, 1929 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Rakhil Levaco file, 1935-1942 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Biographical essay, 1998 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Auto-biographical writings, 1992 (Box-folder 1: 8-10)
  - Clippings, 1923-1962 (Box-folder 1: 11)
- Writings, 1979-1993
  - Articles by Benjamin Levaco, 1982-1993 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - "My 35 years in the Far East,", 1979 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - "Far Eastern Adventure,", 1979 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - "Earthquake of 1923,", 1991 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - "My Maternal Legacy,", 1991 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - "Adventures on the Job,", 1991 (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - "Adventures (Mostly Off The Job)", 1992 (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - "Choices,", undated (Box-folder 1: 19)
- Oppenheimer Casing Company file, 1939-1946
  - Correspondence, 1939-1946 (Box-folder 1: 20)
  - Factory photograph album, before 1949 (Box-folder 1: 21)
  - Panoramic photograph, undated (Box 2)
- Photocopies of photographs, 1901-1992 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Labeled photographs of family scenes, other groups and portraits.
- Photographs, 1912-1940 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  Photographs of family, community and landscapes of Tiensin, and other images.
- The Grammarian of Tientsin Grammar School, 1929-1930 (Box-folder 2: 3-4)
- Ye Olde Grammarian of Tientsin Grammar School, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 1: 5)